Agustí Bau Pericón

■agustibau@gmail.com □+34699540050 ■ in/agustibau • www.agustibau.com

I see myself as a persistent, results-driven, and easygoing software engineer.

I've worked with multiple programming languages and I adapt quickly to codebases and their patterns. When I write code, I prioritize meeting business needs, achieving required performance, organizing code into a modular way and having tests,

I like to care about the products I build, I want them to be loved by our users, be free of bugs and as useful as possible.

I enjoy coding in Vim, running Linux, running scripts, and all that madness.

Outside of work, I love mountain-biking, climbing and anything nature.

EXPERIENCE

Staff software Engineer → **Tech Lead - Clovr-labs**

Jan 2022 - present, Barcelona

I'm part of the chain* team, where we build a highly scalable blockchain analytics system, mainly using Python, Go, Spark, DeltaLake, BigQuery and Redis, everything on Kubernetes.

I started as an individual contributor, and my role has evolved into a "tech lead". Today:

- I've led the architecture of the overall system, data intake, data API, and client APIs. Implementing some parts among the team
- I'm the communication point with our stakeholders, translating requirements into tasks, refining along the way
- I'm the go-to person when we have memory leaks or performance issues
- We have improved the overall team culture (better code standards, contributor reliablity,)

Senior software Engineer - Kasaz

Jul 2020 - Jan 2022, Barcelona

We operated fully remote. I did everything required to keep the platform rolling as at some point I was the only engineer. We had a Ruby on Rails monolith with a frontend in React native and Graphql, on AWS. I did onboard and somewhat manage the newcomers that joined the company Some of the features that we built:

- Search listings by drawing a hand-drawn area or panning the map automatically
- Feed generation to be ingested by traffic providers, involving complex SQL queries that have to run for any amount of listings.
- Alert system to keep users up to date with new listings according to saved searches

Startup incubator - Zinc.vc

Sept 2019 - Feb 2020, London

I was part of "mission 3" where we looked for startup opportunities "for the older population".

Software engineer - Datatiger

Oct 2017 - Nov 2018, London

At Datatiger we built a marketing tool, horizontally scalable following a microservices(ish) architecture using mainly Java and Python on Docker and AWS.

- I was the 8th hire, we developed, designed, and architected key main features of the platform.
- I was responsible of integrating our platform with different systems (email providers, other event providers, ad networks, among others).
- I developed the first parts of the analytics system based on a data lake architecture.

Junior software engineer - King

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017, Barcelona

We developed an internal marketing tool built on Jboss, AWS Redshift and Kafka, using Agile methodologies.

- I implemented end to end image notifications across all King games.
- I developed multiple backend features that incorporated into the ETL process.

Remote For Mac - Self-employed

2013 - 2016~

While at university I developed an Android app, a remote control for Mac devices, for Android. Over time it got downloaded over 200k times, and netted some student money. Better competitors appeared and I lost interest.

EDUCATION